(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-29T13:10:54.066582",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
迫るショッカー 地獄の軍団
Shocker is coming, legions of hell
我らを狙う 黒い影
Black shadows reaching, hunting us down
世界の平和を 守るため
For the peace of the world we stand and fight
ゴーゴー・レッツゴー
Go, go, let's go
輝くマシン
A machine burning bright
ライダー(ジャンプ！)
Rider! (Jump!)
ライダー(キック！)
Rider! (Kick!)
仮面ライダー 仮面ライダー
Kamen Rider, Kamen Rider
ライダー ライダー
Rider! Rider!
ライダー(ジャンプ！)
Rider! (Jump!)
ライダー(キック！)
Rider! (Kick!)
仮面ライダー 仮面ライダー
Kamen Rider, Kamen Rider
ライダー ライダー
Rider! Rider!
あー、火薬の量を間違えて爆発させすぎちゃったよ。
Ah, I messed up the gunpowder amount and exploded way too much.
もう、せっかくの眉毛が燃えちゃうよ。
Man, my eyebrows are gonna burn off!
あ、雪民さん、ありがとう！
Oh, Yukimin, thank you!
みんな、今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for coming today!
そうです！今日はラミィの誕生日です！
That's right! Today is Lamy's birthday!
そして、今年のラミィは一味違います！
And this year's Lamy is a bit different!
今年も体力王で力をつけてきたけど、みんな知ってる？なんでラミィがあんなに頑張ってたか。
I've been building up my strength this year too, but do you know why Lamy worked so hard?
実はね、ヒーローになるためなんだ！
Actually... it's to become a hero!
ズダダダーン！ラミィ！
Zudadadan! Lamy!
でも、ヒーローって言ってもいろんな形があるじゃん？だから今日は自分だけのヒーロー像を探す旅に出ようと思いの…
But hey, there are all kinds of heroes, right? That's why today I thought I'd go on a journey to find my own ideal hero...
なんだんだ？いや、やめろ！
What's this? Hey, stop it!
雪民さん！雪民さん！
Yukimin! Yukimin!
ラミィを守ってくれたの？
You protected Lamy?
さっきもバイク片付けてくれたし、雪民さんは本当にライダー！
You even cleaned up the bike earlier, Yukimin is truly a Rider!
よしよしよしよし…
Good, good, good, good...
あ、別の子もいたの？ちょっとまた敵が来ないか見張っといて！
Oh, there was another one too? Keep a lookout just in case enemies come back!
今日はいろんなゲストを呼んでたくさんのヒーローを見ることができるから楽しみだね！
Today we're inviting various guests so we can see lots of heroes, I'm so excited!
それでは、雪花ラミィ、ヒーロー探しの旅に行ってきまーす！
Well then, Yukihana Lamy, going on a journey to find a hero!
なんて…なんでまた雪民ばかり！僕だって！僕だって！
Why... why is it always Yukimin?! Even I... even I!
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who's that? Who's that? Who's that?
空のかなたに 踊る影
The shadow dancing high in the sky
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
空のかなたに 踊る影
The shadow dancing in the distant sky
白い翼の ガッチャマン
It's the white wings of Gatchaman
命をかけて 飛び出せば
When you risk your life and fly out
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
That's the science ninja skill Firebird
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly! Fly, Fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go! Go, Go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
There's only one earth, there's only one earth
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
海の地獄に 潜む影
The shadow lurking in the hell of the sea
強い勇気の ガッチャマン
With powerful courage, it's Gatchaman
嵐をさいて 雲きれば
When you rend the storm and tear through the clouds
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
That's the science ninja skill Firebird
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly! Fly, Fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go! Go, Go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
There's only one earth, there's only one earth
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
ビルの谷間に 忍ぶ影
The shadow hiding in a valley of buildings
赤い血潮の ガッチャマン
With fiery red blood, it's Gatchaman
夕日を浴びて 駆け出せば
When you bask in the setting sun and run out
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
That's the science ninja skill Firebird
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly! Fly, Fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go! Go, Go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
There's only one earth, there's only one earth
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman Go Fight!
Go! Go! Muscle!
リングに稲妻走り
Lightning strikes the ring
炎の戦士をてらす
Illuminating the fiery warriors
飛び散れ キン肉ビーム
Jump in, Kinniku beam
勝利に向かって
Heading towards victory
私は（ドジ）で 強い（つもり） キン肉マン
I am clumsy, strong like Kinnikuman
走る（すべる） 見事に（ころぶ）
Running and slipping, falling gracefully
ああ 心に愛がなければ
Ah, if there's no love in your heart
スーパーヒーローじゃないのさ
You're not a superhero
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman Go Fight!
Go! Go! Muscle!
嵐の必殺技で
With a storm's special move
けちらす超人レスラー
Defeating the superhuman wrestler
マットに真っ赤な薔薇が 今夜も咲くのさ
Tonight, the bright red rose blooms again on the mat
私は（ドジ）で 強い（つもり） キン肉マン
I am clumsy, strong like Kinnikuman
誰もが（誰もが）待って（いない）
No one (no one) is waiting (anymore)
ああ 果てない夢を追いかけ
Ah, chasing after endless dreams
ああ 果てない夢を追いかけ スーパーヒーローになるのさ
Ah, chasing after endless dreams to become a superhero!
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman Go Fight!
私は（ドジで） 強い（つもり） キン肉マン
I'm (clumsy) and (think I'm) strong, Kinnikuman!
走る（滑る） 見事に（ころぶ）
Running (slipping), falling (gracefully)...
ああ 心に愛がなければ
Ah, if there's no love in your heart...
スーパーヒーローじゃないのさ
You're not a superhero!
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman Go Fight!
ホロライブ生誕3Dヒーローショー
[Title: Hololive Birthday 3D Hero Show]
微かな夕陽
[Song: Faint Sunset]
聞けないように 俯く体を 誰か包んで…壊れる前に
Hiding my face so I can't hear, someone hold me before I shatter...
弾き出し嘲笑い 瞳を打つ 闇への引き金
Laughter bursts forth, hitting my eyes, the trigger to the dark.
踏み込む強さより 抗う痛みなら
Rather than the strength to step in, if it's the pain to fight back...
誰よりも深くで 食らう Conscience
I take it deeper than anyone else—Conscience.
引き千切られたプライドが 心に捲くブリザード
A torn-apart pride whirls like a blizzard in my heart.
ねえ ここから出してよって 叫んでいいの?
Hey, is it okay to scream, "Let me out of here"?
埋もれた声は低い空が いつも救ってくれたね
The low sky has always saved my buried voice.
砕かれた幻想の果て でもまだ終わらせない
At the end of shattered illusions, but it's still not over—
My heart will doubt...?
悲しみ宿った 花びらに乞う
Begging the flower petals harboring sorrow.
涙が落ちた 儚き結晶
Tears fell, fleeting crystals.
未来さえ試されて 闇に賭けて 残った現実
Even the future is tested, betting on the dark, what remains is reality.
黙くに見つめそう 夕日はこの鼓動を生かしてくれるだろう
Gazing silently, the sunset will keep this heartbeat alive.
惑う With the truth
Wandering with the truth.
転んだ今日がまとわりつく 萎れた感情伏せて
Today's stumbles cling to me, hiding withered emotions—
ねえ 早く気付いてよって 叫んでいいの?
Hey, is it okay to scream, "Realize it already"?
傾いた視界に宿る 道は見分けられるか
Dwelling in a tilted field of vision, can you tell the path apart?
ゲームは始まったばかり
The game has only just begun.
この世に潜む現在(いま)を
The present lurking in this world...
My heart will want...
いらない痛みなんてないんだと 素直な自分出して
Expressing my true self, saying there's no such thing as unnecessary pain—
ねえ ここまで来たよって 褒めてもいいの?
Hey, is it okay to praise myself for coming this far?
埋もれた声は低い空が いつも救ってくれたね
The low sky has always saved my buried voice.
砕かれた幻想の果て でもまだ終わらせない
At the end of shattered illusions, but it's still not over—
My heart will believe
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
[Title: Mahou Sentai Magiranger]
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future
OK! オーライ! 勇気をこの手に
OK! Alright! Courage in your hands
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
君が超えたいものは何?
What do you want to overcome?
大空 逆風 昨日の自分
The sky, a headwind, yesterday's self
立ち向かう時 揺れ動く
When confronting it, swaying and shaking
その胸に湧き出すパワー
Power gushing forth in your heart
グリーングランド ピンクストーム
Green Grand, Pink Storm
ブルースプラッシュ イエローサンダー
Blue Splash, Yellow Thunder
レッドファイアー
Red Fire
冒険の始まりさ
It's the start of an adventure
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
限界チャレンジャー
Challenger of the limits
勇気という名の魔法を持っている
You have a magic called courage
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
夢見てフューチャー
Dream of the future
OK! オーライ! 明日をこの手に
OK! Alright! Tomorrow in your hands
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magic Squadron Magiranger
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
君が守りたいものは何?
What do you want to protect?
友情 プライド 見えない絆
Friendship, pride, unseen bonds
くじけそうな時 そばにいる
When you feel like giving up, they're by your side
笑顔に初めて気がつく
Noticing your smile for the first time
タウロス フェアリー
Taurus, Faerie
マーメイド ガルーダ
Mermaid, Garuda
フェニックス
Phoenix
5つの手重ねたら
When five hands are placed together
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
限界チャレンジャー
Challenger of the limits
勇気が勝利の道を示すから
Because courage shows the path to victory
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future
OK! オーライ! この声を届け
OK! Alright! Send this voice out
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magic Squadron Magiranger
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
唸る大地 風は吹き抜け
The earth growls, the wind blows through
たゆたう水 走る雷 燃える炎
The swaying water, running thunder, burning fire
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
限界チャレンジャー
Challenger of the limits
勇気という名の魔法を持っている
You have a magic called courage
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
夢見てフューチャー
Dream of the future
OK! オーライ! 明日をこの手に
OK! Alright! Tomorrow in your hands
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magic Squadron Magiranger
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi Magi Magiranger
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future
OK! オーライ! 勇気をこの手に
OK! Alright! Courage in your hands
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magic Squadron Magiranger
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
とくさんのヒーローと出会えて力はついたけど、
I met Tokusan's hero and got stronger, but...
なんだかいまいちピンとこないんだよねぇ。
Somehow, it doesn't quite click with me yet.
ラミィ
Lamy!
悩んでる顔してどうしたの？
You look troubled, what's wrong?
あ、カナタ！そうなの。
Ah, Kanata! Well, you see.
ヒーローってどうあるべきか分かんなくなっちゃって
I'm not sure how a hero is supposed to act anymore.
力があるだけじゃダメなんだ。
Just having power isn't enough.
大事なのはその力をどう使うかなんだよ。
What matters is how you use that power.
あなた……
You...
握力だけじゃ世界は変えられない。
You can't change the world with grip strength alone.
人々の心を守るのもヒーローの大事な大事な仕事なんだから！
Protecting people's hearts is also a hero's most important job!
そっか。力で守れないものもあるよね。
I see. There are things that power can't protect.
だからヒーローにも強い心が必要なんだ。
That's why heroes need a strong heart, too.
どんなにピンチになっても乗り越えるたびにどんどん強くなる心が！
A heart that grows stronger every time we overcome a pinch!
さあ、僕と一緒に歌って強い心を掴み取ろう！
Now, sing with me and seize a strong heart!
うん！
Yeah!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティで キュアキュア
Pretty and Cure Cure,
ふたりは プリキュア～！
the two of us are Pretty Cure~!
一難去って また一難 ぶっちゃけありえない！！
One trouble after another, honestly, unbelievable!!
制服着てても ふたりは むちゃくちゃタフだし
Even when we're in our uniforms, we are both extremely tough
お互いピンチを乗り越えるたび 強く 近くなるね☆
Every time we overcome a pinch together, we become stronger, and closer☆
強く 強く 近く 近く なるね☆
Stronger, stronger, closer, closer, we become☆
your best! my best! 生きてるんだから
your best! my best! Since we're alive,
失敗なんて メジャない！
failure is nothing!
笑う門に福来たるでしょ！
Good fortune comes to those who smile, right!
ネガティブだって ブッ飛ぶぅ～！
Even negativity will fly away~!
生命の花 咲かせて！ 思いっきり～ もっとバリバリ！！
Let the flower of life bloom! With all our might~ more and more intensely!!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティで キュアキュア
Pretty and Cure Cure,
ふたりは プリキュア～！
the two of us are Pretty Cure~!
たまには放課後のほほんと
Sometimes, chatting relaxedly after school
おしゃべり Very time!
is a very time!
ウワサは恋する乙女の ビタミン剤だもん
Rumors are the vitamin for a maiden in love, you know
闇夜に浮かんだ虹のかけ橋 ここに降りて（ここに降りて）奇跡☆
The rainbow bridge floating in the dark night, a miracle descends here☆
your best! my best! 全力だから
your best! my best! Because we give our all,
友情、愛情、サイコー！
friendship, love, it's the best!
論より証拠の輝くえくぼ 必殺技で ハートキュン！
The sparkling dimples that are better evidence than arguments, with our finishing move, heart kyun!
瞳に、☆（ほし）映して！ 思いっきり～ もっとキラキラ！！
Reflect the stars in your eyes! With all our might~ more and more sparkling!!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
（プリキュア Chu Chu プリキュア Sha ba da ba da）
(Pretty Cure Chu Chu, Pretty Cure Sha ba da ba da)
（Chu Chu Ah Chu Chu Ah）
(Chu Chu Ah Chu Chu Ah)
明日は明日の風吹く マジ意味わかんない
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow, seriously I don't get it
今しか出来ない宿題 ガンバラなくっちゃ！
Homework that I can only do now, I have to do my best!
真逆のキャラでも あい通じてる
Even with opposite characters, our love is connected,
夢を生きる（夢を生きる）チカラ☆
the power to live our dreams☆
your best! my best! 生きてるんだから
your best! my best! Since we're alive,
失敗なんて メジャない！
failure is nothing!
笑う門に福来たるでしょ！
Good fortune comes to those who smile, right!
ネガティブだって ブッ飛ぶぅ～！
Even negativity will fly away~!
生命の花 咲かせて！ 思いっきり～ もっとバリバリ！！
Let the flower of life bloom! With all our might~ more and more intensely!!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティで キュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア～！
Pretty and Cure Cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure~!
(Chu wa)
ありがとう、カナタ！なんとなくだけどヒーローって何かをつかめた気がするよ。
Thank you, Kanata! I feel like I've somehow grasped what a hero is.
よかった！きっとならみなら素敵なヒーローになれるよ。
I'm glad! I'm sure someone like Lamy can become a wonderful hero.
その人をおもんぱかる気持ちを忘れずにね。
Just don't forget to keep others in mind and care for them.
わかった！ラミィなりのヒーロー像を考えてみるよ。
Got it! I'll think about what kind of hero I want to be in my own way.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
それじゃ
Now then...
せいらーーーっ！
Seira~~~!
あー、いっちゃった。
Ah, she went ahead.
よし！この調子で次に行くぞー！
Alright! Let's keep this momentum going and move on to the next!
あ、ごめんね
Ah, sorry.
大福、
Daifuku,
今忙しいの。
I'm busy right now.
後で構ってあげるから。
I'll play with you later.
なんて？
Huh?
なんて僕だけ見てくれないんだ？
Why won't you look at me?
時には僕らは理想を語る非凡な才能の歌者であれ
Sometimes we are extraordinary, talented singers speaking of ideals,
またはキャピタリズムに屈する傀儡の卑しい子犬で
or pitiful puppet puppies bowing down to capitalism,
または虚構が書かれたボードを掲げるデモの一員で
or a member of a protest holding up boards written with fiction,
言わば貴方にとっての癒やし法螺吹き野郎の狼少年だろ
so to speak, a comforting, boastful wolf boy for you.
名声を 体裁を 人生そのものを 潰し合おう
Let's crush each other's fame, appearance, and very lives!
恨んで 恨んで 恨んでもまた妬んで
Resenting, resenting, even while resenting, I'm envious again,
描きたい存在に背中を刺される
and my back is stabbed by the existence I want to portray.
燃やして 燃やして 燃やしても手が震えて
Burning, burning, even while burning, my hands tremble,
嘘を白昼堂々重ねて着込んだ
as I boldly layer and wear my lies in broad daylight.
分かって 分かって 分かって僕の正義を
Understand, understand, understand my justice!
無能な怪物を胸襟で肥やした
I fattened an incompetent monster in my embrace,
踏んで 踏んで 踏んでいるまま選んだ
and chose to keep trampling on it.
その程度の価値の正解はいらない
I don't need such mediocre, trivial correct answers!
時には僕らは希望を託す聖人じみた歌者であれ
Sometimes we are saint-like singers placing our hopes in things,
またはマキャベリズムを隠した見た目だけの置物で
or mere ornamental objects hiding machiavellianism,
または全てに噛み付く振りだけ得意なヒストラーえで
or a fake hysteric good only at biting at everything,
やはり貴方にとっての狡い法螺吹き野郎の狼少年だろう
indeed, probably a cunning, boastful wolf boy for you.
現状の 展望も 変貌も 何もかもが無価値なんだ
The present outlook, transformation, everything is worthless.
存在を 本望を 人生そのものを 潰し合おう
Let's crush each other's existence, true desires, and very lives!
恨んで 恨んで 恨んでもまた妬んで
Resenting, resenting, even while resenting, I'm envious again,
描きたい存在に背中を刺される
and my back is stabbed by the existence I want to portray.
燃やして 燃やして 燃やしても手が震えて
Burning, burning, even while burning, my hands tremble,
嘘を白昼堂々重ねて着込んだ
as I boldly layer and wear my lies in broad daylight.
分かって 分かって 分かって僕の正義を
Understand, understand, understand my justice!
無能な怪物を胸襟で肥やした
I fattened an incompetent monster in my embrace,
踏んで 踏んで 踏んでいるまま選んだ
and chose to keep trampling on it.
その程度の価値の正解はいらない
I don't need such mediocre, trivial correct answers!
時には僕らは思想を諭す英雄的な歌者であれ
Sometimes we are heroic singers preaching ideologies,
つまり貴方にとってのカリスマ気取った極悪非道なペテン師だ
in other words, a heinous, hypocritical swindler acting like a charismatic figure to you.
ねえ、生まれてから今日までの間 どれくらいの御飯で
Hey, from birth until today, with how many meals
私たちはできてるかな 毎日ありがとう
are we made? Thank you every day!
もし食卓からおいしいが消えてしまったら あ、迷わずに
If delicious food disappeared from the dining table, ah, without hesitation,
どこにいたって 何をしてたって 取り戻しにいこう
wherever we are, whatever we're doing, let's go get it back!
あれは記念日の記憶 何気ないあの味も
That is the memory of an anniversary, and that casual taste too—
忘れたりしない ずっと一緒だって伝えなくちゃ
I won't ever forget. I have to tell you we'll always be together!
必ず守りたいこの味は キミと笑い合う毎日の
This taste I surely want to protect is the warmest roadside beacon
一番傍で照らす あたたかい道しるべなんだ
that shines right beside me, illuminating our smiling days.
みんなと今胸を熱くするオモイ 育んでこれからも
Fostering the feelings warming our hearts with everyone, from now on too,
大切に刻もう キズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
let's carve it into our hearts preciously: a speciality bound by bonds!
ホラ、キミに届く おいしいの中の たくさんのストーリー！
Hey, reaching you, within the deliciousness, are countless stories!
めぐりめぐって ここにあって 奇跡みたいだよ
Going around and coming here, it feels like a miracle.
約束、繋げたい 今がある キミと分かち合いたい 未来へと
Promises, a present we want to connect, toward a future we want to share with you.
くじけそうな時も 負けないココロで立ち向かう
Even when feeling discouraged, we'll stand and face it with an unbeaten heart.
みんなの しあわせなエナジーが作る この日々がうれしいよ
We're so happy for these days created by everyone's happy energy.
デリシャスにあつまれ！ パーティは続いていくね
Gather for deliciousness! The party will keep going.
世界中で今も それぞれのストーリー
All around the world, even now, everyone has their own story.
ひとりずつができることを がんばってるから
Because each of us is doing our best with what we can do.
必ず守りたい この味は キミと笑い合う毎日の
We definitely want to protect this taste of laughing with you every day.
いちばん傍で照らす あたたかい道しるべなんだ
It's a warm guidepost shining right by your side.
みんなと 今胸を 熱くする想い 育んでこれからも
With everyone, cherishing these feelings that warm our hearts right now, from now on too,
大切に刻もう キズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
Let's engrave it dearly: a speciality bound by bonds.
約束、繋げたい 今がある キミと分かち合いたい 未来へと
Promises, a present we want to connect, toward a future we want to share with you.
くじけそうな時も 負けないココロで立ち向かう
Even when feeling discouraged, we'll stand and face it with an unbeaten heart.
みんなの しあわせなエナジーが作る この日々がうれしいよ
We're so happy for these days created by everyone's happy energy.
デリシャスにあつまれ！ パーティは続いていくね
Gather for deliciousness! The party will keep going.
大切に刻もう キズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
Let's engrave it dearly: a speciality bound by bonds.
やっぱりねぽらぼね！ねぽらぼ！ねぽらぼ！
As expected of Neporabo! Neporabo! Neporabo!
やっと来てくれた！
You finally came!
許さない…許さない！
I won't forgive you... I won't forgive you!
うわぁぁぁ！た、体育！
Aah! P-PE!
やみふく
[Yamifuku]
まさか、あれはラミィにかまってもらえず負の感情が爆発して…
No way, could that be... because she didn't get enough attention from Lamy, her negative emotions exploded...
闇落ちした、やみふく？
She fell into darkness... Yamifuku?
そんなん…体育、元に戻って！
That... PE, go back to normal!
うるさい！
Shut up!
こうなったら力づくでも元に戻してあげる！
If it comes to this, we'll force you back to normal!
元に戻って！
Go back to normal!
連射すぎじゃない？これ
Isn't that too rapid-fire?!
どう…どうだ？
How... how is that?
くそー！
Damn it!
ラミィ、待って！
Lamy, wait!
ちくしょう！
Damn it!
かまって…！
Pay attention to me...!
わー、ラミちゃんが闇落ちさせられたー！
Wah, Lamy-chan was made to fall into darkness!
これでラミィとずっと一緒だ！
With this, I'll be together with Lamy forever!
ラミィが相手でも止めるしかないよ！
Even if our opponent is Lamy, we have no choice but to stop her!
確かにラミィはタフだしね、ちょっとぐらい痛くても平気でしょ！
True, Lamy is tough, so a little pain should be fine!
あ、ちょうどいいところに。雪民、手おかして！
Ah, right on time. Yukimin, lend me a hand!
雪民、いっけえええー！
Yukimin, gooooo!
雪民、ごめんなあああ！
Yukimin, sorryyyyy!
いっけええええ！
Go!
かまして！
Let loose!
やめろおおおお！
Stop itnnnn!
エマージェンシー！
Emergency!
超ラミィ！
Super Lamy!
えー、今度はラミィでっかくなっちゃったんだけどー！
Man, now Lamy's gotten huge!
しかたなし、あれを使おう！
Oh well, let's use that!
お、あれ？
Oh, that?
そっか！よしっ！
I see! Alright!
みんな！力を貸して！ラミィのいいところをたくさん言って、
Everyone! Lend me your strength! Say lots of nice things about Lamy,
祝福パワーをためて攻撃だ！
store up blessing power, and attack!
ラミィ！ラミィ！
Lamy! Lamy!
よし！いい感じ！このまま観客席の大家もラミィのいいところをめっちゃ言ってって！
Alright! Looking good! Audience members, keep shouting out Lamy's great points!
で、うちのもよ…
And what about mine...
え？うちのもよ？言うの？
Huh? Yours too? Should we?
あの、ラミィのいいところ言ってこう。
Um, let's go ahead and list Lamy's great points.
そしたら多分ラミィも元に戻るからね？いつもの感じね？
Then Lamy will probably return to normal, right? Like usual, right?
じゃあいくよ！せーの！まばたき！
Alright, here we go! Ready, set! Blink!
ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがある！
Lamy-chan, there's something we want to tell you!
なーにー！？
What is it!?
なーにー！
ねぇねのくだらないLINE、秒で返事してくれてありがとう！
Thank you for replying in a second to Nene's silly LINE messages!
えー、優しい！
Aww, so kind!
えー、いいじゃん！これはちょっと、いい感じのあれ？
Hey, that's not bad! Is this... a good vibe?
やめて！止めて！止めて！止めて！止めて！
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
じゃあ次！お前の！お前の！ポルカいけ！
Alright next! Yours! Yours! Polka, go!
ラミィに言いたいことがあります！
There's something I want to tell Lamy!
なーにー！
What is it!?
いつもさ、こんな頼りないうちらのことまとめてくれたり、突っ込んでくれたりしてくれて、本当に感謝してるんだ。
Always summarizing us unreliable ones and poking fun at us, we're really grateful.
だからラミィ、お願い！元の姿に戻って！
So Lamy, please! Return to your normal form!
どうだ！いいんじゃない？
How's that! Isn't that good?
いけいけ！次！次！ポルカいけ！
Go go! Next! Next! Polka, go!
じゃあ次！お前の！
Alright next! Yours!
ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがあります！ なーにー！
There's something I want to tell Lamy-chan! What is it!?
いつも、獅子白がこぼきをいっぱいすると、全部に突っ込んでくれてありがとう！
Whenever Shishiro makes lots of slip-ups, thanks for pointing out every single one of them!
おい！いいじゃん！いいじゃん！ありがとう！あー、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと！
Hey! That's good! That's good! Thank you! Ah, more, more, more, more!
次いけ！次いけ！2個目！2個目！
Go next! Go next! Second one! Second one!
そう、2周、2周！
Yeah, second round, second round!
えー、ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがあります！ なーにー！
Um, there's something I want to tell Lamy-chan! What is it!?
秒で返事してくれるけど、スタンプで秒で笑らそうとするの、やめてね！
You reply in seconds, but stop trying to make me laugh in seconds with stamps!
下がるんじゃない？
Isn't it going down?
上がるはず！上がるはず！大丈夫か！いけいけいけいけ！
It should go up! It should go up! Is it okay? Go go go go!
オラオラオラ！もういっかい！
Ora ora ora! Once more!
えー、ラミィに言いたいことがあります！ なーにー！
Um, there's something I want to tell Lamy! What is it!?
これをきっかけに初期ラミィからやり直してみるのもどうでしょうか？
How about using this as an opportunity to redo things from initial Lamy?
バカお前、やめろ、やめろよ！
Idiot, you, stop it, stop it!
決めるぞ！決めるぞ！決めるぞ！決めるぞ！
Decide it! Decide it! Decide it! Decide it!
ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがあります！ なーにー！
There's something I want to tell Lamy-chan! What is it!?
いつも電波ラボを大切にしてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for always taking such good care of Denpa Lab!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
え？もっと？もっと？走る走る！
Huh? More? More? Run run!
これはどうなるんだ？
What is this going to do?
え？どういうこと？やってくれるんじゃないでしょ？え？あー、落とした！
Huh? What do you mean? You're not going to do it? Eh? Ah, dropped it!
え？これは？でも、これはパワーがたまったんじゃないか？
Eh? What's this? But, hasn't power built up?
よしよしよし！ラミィ！元に戻ってくれ！
Alright alright alright! Lamy! Return to normal!
いけ！電ポラも気合のビーム！
Go! Denpola's spirited beam!
ラミィ！ラミィ！
Lamy! Lamy!
うう……
Ugh...
ラミィはいったい……あ、元に戻った！よかったぁ！
Where on earth was Lamy... Ah, back to normal! Thank God!
大福の力で闇落ちしてたんだよ。いやでも、正直、普段のラミィと全然変わんなかったから、うん、元に戻ってよかった。
I was consumed by darkness through Daifuku's power. Well, honestly, it wasn't really any different from normal Lamy, so yeah, I'm glad I'm back to normal.
え？おれ？おれ？いく？
Eh? Me? Me? Go?
大福、ごめんなさい。ちゃんと言ってあげられなくて。
Daifuku, I'm sorry. I wasn't able to properly tell you.
ラミィ、
Lamy,
他人を思いやる気持ちが大事って教わったばかりなのに、うまくできなくてごめんね。
Even though I was just taught that caring for others is important, I'm sorry I couldn't do it right.
やっぱりラミィには、大福や雪民さんがいないとだめなの。
As expected, Lamy needs Daifuku and Yukimin around.
ラミィ！
Lamy!
大福、ずっとずっと一緒だよ！
Daifuku, we'll be together forever and ever!
完
[Complete]
ということで、みんなラミィの生誕祭どうだったですか？
So everyone, how was Lamy's birthday celebration?
もちろん最高でした！
Of course, it was amazing!
ラミィ誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday, Lamy!
えーということでね、まだ終わりませんよ。
So, it's not over yet!
重大告知が2つあります！
There are two major announcements!
まずは、こちら！
First, this one!
雪花ラミィ誕生日記念 2025 グッズ
Yukihana Lamy Birthday 2025 Merchandise
詳しく紹介していきたいと思います。
So I'd like to introduce them in detail.
まずは、こちら、アクリルスタンド！
First is this, the acrylic stand!
フード付きタオルを身に付けたラミィの元気な姿となっております。
It features Lamy looking energetic in her hooded towel.
おそろいトレーナー！
Matching sweatshirt!
あー、これ欲しかったやつ！かわいい！
Ah, I wanted this! So cute!
サイバー仕様のトレーナーとおそろいのデザインとなっております。
It features a cyber-style design matching Lamy's.
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー ファンタジー衣装 ver.
Plushie keychain: Fantasy outfit version.
ユニーリアのあの夏衣装を身にまとったラミィのぬいぐるみキーホルダーとなっております。
It's a plushie keychain of Lamy in her Uneelia summer outfit.
雪民フード付きタオルとなっております！
Yukimin hooded towel!
雪民さんの顔がフードになっているタオルね。
A towel featuring Yukimin's face as the hood.
今後イベントとかあった時にこういうのを身につけてアピールしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you wear this to events!
複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードとなっております！
A postcard with duplicate signature and message!
かわいいでしょ？みんなこれやって！ありがとうございます！
Cute, right? Everyone do this! Thank you!
以上、雪花ラミィ誕生日記念2025グッズでした！
That's all for the 2025 birthday merch!
告知2つ目は、新曲となっております！
The second announcement is a new song!
この配信の後21時からフルアニメーションMVが公開されます！
A full animation MV will be released at 21:00!
初めてのフルアニメーションMVとなっております！
It's my very first full animation MV!
各種音楽サイトのリリースはこのあと0時から配信されますのでよろしくお願いします！
Release on music sites starts at 0:00 tonight!
みなさん今日はたくさんたくさんありがとう！バイバイ！
Everyone, thank you so much today! Bye-bye!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible ☆ Serious Survivor!
ギリギリの綱渡り
Walking a tightrope by a thread,
弱音はポケットの奥
weakness hidden deep in my pocket.
しまい込んだら ただ進むだけ
Once packed away, I just keep moving forward.
こけだって 即リスタート
Even if I trip, it's an instant restart;
そこからがスタートライン
that's where the starting line begins.
もう止まらないよ
There's no stopping me now!
迷いなんてものも
Even hesitation—
不器用でも 前へ
even clumsily, moving ahead!
しょげてるヒマはないし
There's no time to be feeling down,
ハイテンションで行こうぜん！
let's go with super high tension!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible, serious survivor!
ゼロからでも何度だって
Even from zero, no matter how many times,
メンタル最強モードです 見ててね★
it's my strongest mental mode, watch me★
限界歓迎チャレンジャー！
Limit-welcome challenger!
そう不安なんてさ 笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's laugh away any anxiety.
最前線 君しだい
The front lines depend on you.
さあ行くよ Ready Go! ついてきてよねっ★
Come on, ready go! Follow me, okay?★
トラブルさえ追い風
Even trouble becomes a tailwind!
ピンチもドキドキのスパイス
Even a crisis is an exciting spice.
"Bring it on!" 胸を張れ
"Bring it on!" Hold your head high.
遠回りも Go Go
Taking the long way is also go go!
転んでも Try だ！
Even if you fall, try!
自分史上一番へ
Towards the best in my life,
アクセル全開 ノンストップ！
accelerator wide open, non-stop!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible, serious survivor!
ブレーキなんてお飾りでしょ？
Brakes are just for decoration, right?
ハート高鳴りモードで 感じて★
Feel it in my heart-pounding mode★
完全燃焼フィニッシャー！
Complete combustion finisher!
そう誰より強く夢を叫ぼう
Let's shout our dreams louder than anyone.
最終章 君しだい
The final chapter depends on you.
さあ行こう Ready Go! 置いてかないからっ★
Come on, ready go! I won't leave you behind★
最強☆最愛チームメイツ！
Strongest and most beloved teammates!
君の声がパワーソース
Your voice is my power source.
輝いて 駆けてこう 未来へ Fly high...
Shine and run forward, fly high to the future...
超ハイテンションで行こうぜん！！
Let's go with super high tension!!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible, serious survivor!
ゼロからでも何度だって
Even from zero, no matter how many times,
メンタル最強モードです 見ててね★
it's my strongest mental mode, watch me★
限界歓迎チャレンジャー！
Limit-welcome challenger!
そう不安なんてさ 笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's laugh away any anxiety.
最前線 君しだい
The front lines depend on you.
さあ行くよ Ready Go! もっともっと ついてきてよねっ★
Come on, ready go! Follow me even more, okay?★
みんな！今日のライブどうだった？
Everyone! How was today's live?
ラミィヒーローになれたかな？
Did I become a Lamy hero?
新曲も、いままでのラミィにはないかっこいい曲だったでしょ？
Wasn't the new song cooler than anything I've done before?
みんなの感想、今日のハッシュタグをつけていっぱい聞かせてね！
Let me hear all your thoughts with today's hashtag!
そして、この配信のあと21時から、新曲「無敵☆本気だサバイバー！」のフルアニメーションMVが公開されます！
And right after this stream at 9 PM, the full animation MV for "Muteki Honki da Survivor!" will premiere!
ついにやってきました！フルアニメーション！
It's finally here! A full animation!
今回のMVには、ラミィの大好きなものがたくさん詰まっています。
This MV is packed with so many things Lamy loves.
このライブの後、直接MVに飛ぶようになっているので、みんなこのまま待っててね！
After this live, it will link directly to the MV, so everyone wait right here!
さて、まだもう少し時間があるから、MVをちらみせしちゃいます！
Now, we still have a little time left, so I'll give you a sneak peek of the MV!
どうぞ！
Here it goes!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible, serious survivor!
ゼロからでも何度だって
Even from zero, no matter how many times,
メンタル最強モードです 見ててね★
it's my strongest mental mode, watch me★
限界歓迎チャレンジャー！
Limit-welcome challenger!
そう不安なんてさ 笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's laugh away any anxiety.
最前線 君しだい
The front lines depend on you.
さあ行くよ Ready Go! ついてきてよねっ★
Come on, ready go! Follow me, okay?★
ラミレンジャー 生誕3Dヒーローショー
Lamy Ranger: Birthday 3D Hero Show